Welcome to our intro to new seller incentives.
In this video, we'll cover the eligibility requirements and perks of the new seller incentives program.
Starting your selling journey in the Amazon store?
This program can help kickstart your business by investing in your success early on.
The new seller incentives program is a curated suite of benefits designed to scale your business,
promote your products and grow your brand.
You're eligible to receive new seller incentives if you're registered as a professional seller and
launched your first buyable product in the US, UK, Germany, Italy, France, Spain or Japan on or
after January 1, 2022.
You're also eligible for the program if you're an existing seller looking to expand your business
to other Amazon stores.
For instance, if you're currently only selling your products in the US store, you become eligible
for new seller incentives when you list your first buyable product in the UK store.
The program offers four perks tied to the following, Amazon brand registry, fulfillment by Amazon
or FBA, coupons and Amazon ads.
Let's take a closer look at each.
Once you've enrolled in Amazon brand registry, you'll receive a 5% bonus credit on up to $1 million
in branded sales or for the duration of one year after you've become eligible for the bonus, whichever
comes first.
This bonus is applied to your referral fees.
For example, let's say you made $500,000 in branded sales in a single month.
In this case, you'd be eligible for a bonus credit of $25,000 that will automatically be applied
as a discount to the following month's referral fees.
With the amount you earned back, you can invest in other growth opportunities for your business.
For example, you could use advertising tools to help promote your products and grow your customer
audience.
You could create deals that help make your products more enticing to customers or invest in new
product opportunities for your brand.
With new seller incentives, you'll also receive credits for Amazon Vine and Amazon Transparency
once you enroll in those programs.
You will receive $200 credits for Vine, our tool to kickstart your product reviews through selected
customers enrolled in the program.
You will receive $100 credits for Amazon Transparency, our product serialization service that helps
identify and prevent counterfeit products.
One of the other perks applies to fulfillment by Amazon or FBA.
Once joining the new seller incentives program, you'll receive $100 in credits for inventory shipping
fees when using the Amazon partnered carrier program or $200 in credits for fulfillment fees when
using Amazon Global Logistics.
You'll also be auto-enrolled in the FBA New Selection Program, which offers free monthly storage
and return processing for eligible new to FBA ASINs.
You can search FBA New Selection Program in Seller Central to learn more about the program and its
benefits.
When you use FBA, you can also become eligible to receive $50 in credits for your sponsored products
campaign's promotional clicks.
Sponsored products campaigns can help increase the discoverability of your products as they appear
in search results or on product detail pages.
Finally, if you're using coupons, you'll get $50 in coupon credits through the new seller incentives
program.
With coupons, you can offer percentage or money-off discounts to help increase the visibility of
your products and make them more attractive to customers.
This concludes our intro to the new seller incentives program.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!